BENJAMIN PORTIS

Portland, OR https://benjaminportis.com/

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Customer-focused Software Developer with extensive experience delivering complex automation software from requirements testing to monitoring and upkeep while maintaining extensive documentation. Collaborative problem solver awarded for cross-departmental teamwork in troubleshooting system issues and developing resolutions. Trusted mentor with success training and coaching interns through code review, design patterns, and Agile process. Detail oriented programmer driven by continuous improvement, scalability, performance, and reliability.

Please view my website (Link found at the top right), which I created using Javascript, React, Next.js and Node.js, with cloud integration/security from Auth0, hosted on Vercel. View some of my personal projects at

https://github.com/AutoTau.

AREAS OF EXPERTISE

Object Oriented Programming | Agile Development | Software Development | C# Automation |
Cross-Functional Communication & Collaboration | Requirements Analysis | Observability Development |
REST API Development

C#, .NET Core, ASP.NET Core, WPF, Javascript, React, Node.js, Next.js, C++, Java, Android, PowerShell, SQL, NoSQL, MongoDB, Linux, Auth0

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Intel | Portland, OR | 06/2018 - Present

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

01/2020 - Present

Creating observability solutions for complex factory automation systems and delivering expert customer service through on-call support to solve automation issues within Intel's primary factory research and development facility to ensure the factory's production quality and output.

- **Driving observability and operational best practices** by implementing custom scripts and Elastic stack, accelerating resolution of production issues and simplified identification of long-term trends and issues with software insertions.
- Achieving mastery of ticket solving proficiency independently and in a timely manner. Recognized for excellent ticket
 documentation and breadth of knowledge and training across multiple factories in the US and abroad.
- Managing application health and factory output across multiple technology stacks including desktop C# WPF applications, ASP.NET Core, VB.NET, C, C++.
- Managing large-scale bare metal data centers using software automation, including large scale software insertions to production systems, and monitoring and triggering containments and reboots for software updates and emergencies.
- Bridging the gap between customer and developer providing on-call support to solve challenging automation issues, working with customers to troubleshoot and achieve resolutions quickly. Digging through logs and databases to ensure factory output.

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT INTERN

06/2018 - 01/2020

Developed test automation software for Bluetooth and WiFi technology and built custom automation software, APIs, and C# desktop applications to aid in the automation of hardware validation and certification.

- Identified and implemented areas for improvement in automation to drive operational efficiencies with multi-threaded C# implementations. Maintained and contributed to continuous integration software (Jenkins based), providing support and bug fixes for teams across multiple geos.
- Achieved departmental recognition award for C# WPF application automating the process of Packaging, Attestation, and Submission of Bluetooth and WiFi drivers, reducing manual work by 90%.
- Mentored and coached two interns in C#, how to build WPF applications, MVC and MVVM design patterns, Jira board, and Agile process.

Portland State University | Portland, OR | 10/2017 - 06/2018

HELP DESK VOLUNTEER

10/2017 - 06/2018

Provided systems administration for the Maseeh College of Engineering and Computer Science through upkeep of systems. Helped students and faculty resolve technical issues.

• **Delivered exceptional customer service** to diverse customer base and developed deeper understanding of system administration, information technology, and user support, from Linux based systems to Windows based systems.

EDUCATION